Emory University, School of Law, Emory Law School faculty committee records, 1963-2010
Emory Law School Archives
Emory Law School faculty committee records, 1963-2010
Emory University. School of Law.
L-007
4 linear ft. (8 boxes)
Records from various Emory Law School faculty committees including meeting minutes, memoranda and other correspondence related to the functions of the committees.
Emory University Emory Law School Archives
Source
Transfer.
Restrictions on Access
Unrestricted access.
Administrative History
The Emory University School of Law was established in 1916. The Emory Board of Trustees named the new enterprise L.Q.C. Lamar School of Law. Lamar had graduated from Emory College in 1845 and had a distinguished career as a statesman, scholar and lawyer. The law and theology schools were the first academic buildings completed on the Emory Quadrangle. In 1919, the law school hired its first dean, Samuel C. Williams. By 1923, the American Bar Association classified Emory as a "Class A" school.
In 1972, the present day Gambrell Hall was constructed and named in honor of E. Smythe Gambrell's parents. E. Smythe Gambrell, joined the adjunct faculty in 1924 and served on the faculty until the eve of World War II. The Hugh F. MacMillan Law Library, adjacent to Gambrell Hall, opened its doors in 1995.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of records from various faculty committees, including Academic Standings; Admissions; Curriculum; Dean Search; Faculty Appointments; Library; Placement and others. The bulk of the records are from 1968-1989 and contain meeting minutes, memoranda and other correspondence related to the functions of the committees.
Arrangement Note
Arranged alphabetically by committee name, then chronologically.
Container List
- Committee assignments, 1963-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic standings, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Academic standings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Academic standings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Academic standings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Academic standings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Academic standings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Academic standings, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Academic standings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Academic standings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Academic standings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Academic standings, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Academic standings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Academic standings, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Academic standings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Academic standings, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Academic standings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Academic standings, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Academic standings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Academic standings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Academic standings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Academic standings, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Academic standings, no date (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Admissions, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Admissions, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Admissions, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Admissions, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Admissions, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Admissions, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Admissions, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Admissions, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Admissions, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Admissions, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Admissions, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Admissions, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Admissions, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Admissions, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Admissions, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Admissions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Admissions, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Ad hoc, 1968-1983, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Advisory committee on chaired professorships, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Clinical, 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Clinical, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Clinical, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Clinical, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Clinical, 2002-2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Colloquium Scholarship, 2006
- Committee structure, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Committee to review faculty procedures, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Curriculum, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Curriculum, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Curriculum, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Curriculum, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Curriculum, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Curriculum, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Curriculum, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Curriculum, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Curriculum, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Curriculum, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Curriculum, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Curriculum, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Curriculum, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Curriculum, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Curriculum, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Curriculum, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Curriculum, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Curriculum, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Curriculum, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Curriculum, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Curriculum, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Curriculum, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Curriculum, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Curriculum, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Curriculum, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Curriculum, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Curriculum, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Curriculum, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Curriculum, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Curriculum, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Curriculum, 2009-Legislation and regulation course (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Curriculum, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Curriculum, 2010-Upper-level writing task force (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Curriculum, no date (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Curriculum, no date-Adoption of semester system (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Curriculum, no date-Scheduling subcommittee (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Dean search, 1972-Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Dean search, 1972-Resumes (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Dean search, 1972-Memoranda and lists (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Dean search, 1972-Student advisory committee (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Dean search, 1979-1980-Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Dean search, 1979-1980-Lists of candidates (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Dean search, 1979-1980-Memoranda (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Dean search, 1984-Memoranda (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Executive, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Executive, 1972-1979, no date (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Executive, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Faculty appointments, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Faculty appointments, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Faculty appointments, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Faculty appointments, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Faculty appointments, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Faculty appointments, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Faculty appointments, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Faculty appointments, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Faculty appointments, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Faculty appointments, 1977 (procedures) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Faculty appointments, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Faculty appointments, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Faculty appointments, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Faculty appointments, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Faculty appointments, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Faculty appointments, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Faculty appointments, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Faculty appointments, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Faculty appointments, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Faculty appointments, no date (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Faculty grading, 1986 -1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Faculty research writing, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Grading, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Graduate, 1971-1980, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Joint degree, 1972-1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Law Review Moot Court, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Law School council, 1975-1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Library (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Library development, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Library policy, 1968-1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Long-range planning, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Long-range planning, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Long-range planning, 1979-1980 (addendum) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Placement, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Policy goals, 1987-1988, no date (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Publications, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Scholarship recruiting, 1965-1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Select committee on the journals, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Skills training and field placement, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Student affairs, 1968-1973, no date (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Student curriculum, no date (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Woodruff endowment, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 14)